Mohammed Abdulsalam

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled web developer with over 3 year of experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, 2 year of experience in PHP, MySQL. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Laravel, React, and Vue.js. I worked on several projects using native PHP and MySQL/MariaDB, and have experience designing REST APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : PHP, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, TeX

Frameworks : Laravel, PHPUnit, React.js

Libraries : laravel-websockets, laravel-medialibrary, laravel-echo, react-router, styled-components, Socket.IO

Databases : MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite

Methodoligies : BEM

Concepts : OOP, MVC, HMVC, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, OAuth, ERD Design, SRS Design

Dev Tools : Vim, XDebug, Vite, Git, Github Actions, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cron, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer Volunteer

Jan 2023 - Present

Location: Alexandria, Egypt

UCCD KSU

GDSC KSU

Remote - Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

Remote - Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive student management website using React.js
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from backend

Vice Head of Web Development Committee

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- · Make sure the plan is suitable for members
- Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility, through number of sessions

Feb 2022 – Present

Freelance

- Design and development of websites using HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- · Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

EDUCATION

University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 – Jul 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.25/4

PROJECTS

Online ChatDemoPHP, Laravel, HMVC, SCSSPrivate

• Online customer service chat written in PHP / Laravel. Build with HMVC architectural pattern

- Utilized laravel-websockets & laravel-echo to provide real time communication
- Used laravel-medialibrary to facilitate media storing and retrieval

• Developed **REST API** for clients, and chat frontend using **Blade** and **Javascript**

UCCD WebsiteDemoReact.js, GitPrivate

• Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

- Utilized **responsive design** to ensure compatibility across all devices
- · Communicated with backend using a RESTful API

Bookopia Demo
PHP, Laravel, MVC, SCSS Source Code

- A library management system written in PHP / Laravel. Build with MVC architectural pattern
- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, and SCSS
- Utilized Laravel Components to enhance the modularity of the frontend
- Extended Blade funcionality by writing customized Directives, that help us write less code

Salem Clinic Website PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git Private

- Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a **cronjob** to backup data periodically

Clinic Management System (ERP)

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- · Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned ERD based on this analysis
- Used XDebug to facilitate debugging process, and PHPUnit to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used Socket.IO under Node.js to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients

CERTIFICATIONS

• ITI - Web Development Using PHP (150 hrs.)